Discover a world you've only imagined.
Dinosaur is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Ralph Zondag.
An orphaned dinosaur raised by lemurs joins an arduous trek to a
sancturary after a meteorite shower destroys his family home.
Aladar (voice), played by D. B. Sweeney.
Plio (voice), played by Alfre Woodard.
Yar (voice), played by Ossie Davis.
Zini (voice), played by Max Casella.
Suri (voice), played by Hayden Panettiere.
Kron (voice), played by Samuel E. Wright.
Dinosaur is a 2000 American live-action animated  adventure film directed by Ralph Zondag and
Eric Leighton and written by John Harrison, Robert Nelson Jacobs, and Walon Green.
Produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation and The
Secret Lab, it stars the voices of D.
Sweeney, Alfre Woodard, Ossie Davis, Max Casella, Hayden Panettiere, Samuel E.
Wright, Julianna Margulies, Peter Siragusa, Joan Plowright, and Della Reese.
The film follows a young Iguanodon who was adopted and raised
by a family of lemurs on a tropical island.
They are forced to the mainland by a catastrophic meteorite impact; setting out to find a new home, they join a herd of dinosaurs heading for
the "Nesting Grounds", but must contend with the group's harsh leader, as well as external dangers such as predatory Carnotaurus.
The initial idea was conceived in 1986 by Phil Tippett and Paul Verhoeven, which
they conceived as a darker, naturalistic film about dinosaurs.
The project underwent numerous iterations with multiple directors attached.
In 1994, Walt Disney Feature Animation began development on the project and spent
several years developing the software to create the dinosaurs.
While the characters in Dinosaur are computer-generated, most of the
backgrounds are live-action and were filmed on location.
A number of backgrounds were found in various continents such as the Americas
and Asia; various tepuis and Angel Falls also appear in the film.
With a budget of $127.5 million, Dinosaur was reportedly the
most expensive computer-animated film at the time.
Dinosaur is also the first film from Walt Disney
Feature Animation to be 3D animated.
Dinosaur was released on May 19, 2000, to mixed reviews from critics, who praised the film's opening
sequence, soundtrack and animation, but criticized the story, screenplay and lack of originality.
The film grossed $349.8 million worldwide, becoming the
fifth highest-grossing film of 2000.
It became the fourth best-selling home video release of 2001, selling
10.6 million copies and garnering $198 million in sales.
The film explores themes of cataclysm, asteroid, villain, comet, migration.
The tone is emotional.